# SeyedHosseinMirian

# FRONT END DEVELOPER / UI & UX DESIGNER

Website: http://hoseinmirian.com/

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hossein-mirian/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/hossein-mirian/</a>
GitLab: <a href="https://gitlab.com/users/hosein-mirian/projects">https://gitlab.com/users/hosein-mirian/projects</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/hoseinmirian">https://github.com/hoseinmirian</a>

Email: hosein.mirian@gmail.com

Phone: +44 7376799008

Residence Country: United Kingdom

MSc Advanced Computer Science graduate of BCU University and current University of Oxford Front-End Developer/Researcherr with huge practical experience in React, VUE ANDROID, JAVA, PHP and MYSQ. More than 12 years, an experienced programmer being involved in projects worldwide.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Java, PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Vue, React Native, Redux, Vuex, React Js, Bootstrap, Bulma. UI Designing, UX, SQLite, MySQL, Laravel, CodeIgniter, MVC, Git.

**Software**: Adobe Design package (Photoshop, Flash, Director, Premier, Illustrator, Muse), Eclipse, Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, NetBeans, Web Storm, Microsoft Studio Code.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

University of Oxford - Oxford, UK (https://github.com/FAIRsharing/fairsharing.github.io)

VueJs developer/UIUX Designer

jan 2020 to now

- Working in a professional team consisting of PHDs and software engineers to develop a fair system for sharing publishers, curators' data based on an accessible, findable and integrated strategy.
- I am working as front end developer and UI/UX designer to develop the FairSharing website.

MihanFood - Tehran,Iran (http://www.himart.co:1987) (Sample Code Video)

Vuels developer May 2018 to dec 2019

- Using Vue, Vuex, html css and bootstrap to develop a startup name Himart startup project which is an online super market.

KAWeb - Lichfield, UK (www.kaweb.co.uk) (SAMPLE Video Demo) (SAMPLE WEB ONLINE 2)

Laravel and CodeIgniter developing Apprenticeship

Sep to Oct 2018

- I am cooperating and learning at the same time, working on the company's project written mostly by Laravel and CodeIgniter along with Vue Js.
- Whilst being there I also developed my personal website using Laravel and Vue Js.

#### **Birmingham City University**

Demonstrator in Faculty of Computing

Sep to Dec 2018

 As a demonstrator, I was responsible for assisting lecturers to answer the students' questions regarding Object Oriented Programming in Java and cooperated with another lecturer in the Android module.

## GravitiChain - Birmingham, UK (Watch App Demo1) (Watch App Demo2) (Rec Letter)

Aug to Sep 2018

React Native Developer

- GravitiChain is a young startup company based in Birmingham working around Block Chain technology and banking systems. I was working as the react native developer to produce native application which is a CRM system, fully compatible with all mobile platforms.
- Used React Native, AMAZON AWS, JavaScript, PHP and MYSQL to create the CRM services.

# Birmingham City University (Progressive Web App project). (SAMPLE ONLINE)

Apr to Jun 2018

Fullstack Developer

- Used CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap4, PHP, React, and HTML5 to design a flexible, clean and responsive website.
- Used MYSQL to store the data.
- Good sample of front and back end development using the latest technologies.

## **Birmingham City University**

Sep 2017 to Sep 2018

Student Ambassador

- As a demonstrator, I was responsible for assisting lecturers to answer the students' questions regarding Object Oriented Programming in Java and cooperated with another lecturer in the Android module.

# **ENGLISH WITH SMART SUBTITLE (Watch App Demo)**

May 2016 to May 2017

Graphic Designer & Android Developer

- Completely designed and programmed from scratch.
- Help many users to learn English through watching movies in the app
- One of the most popular apps in the Iranian biggest app store, Café Bazar.
- 85% positive feedback from users.
- Combination of years of experience and English tutoring.

# KDG - FOOD Co (www.kdg-food.com)

Jan 2014 to Apr 2016

Web Graphic Designer & Android Developer

- Designed and created six cutting-edge mobile apps using the latest technologies to meet Managers demand.
- Designed Graphic Banners and catalog of the company's products.
- Designed and developed company's website using PHP, jQuery, JavaScript and Bootstrap.

#### LANGUAGE QUALIFICATION

- **TOEFL** IBT English language test (overall score:90)
- TEFL English Teaching Certificate

#### **EDUCATION**

- Birmingham City University, MSc Advanced Computer Science
- Payam Higher Education University, BS Computer Software

2017 - 2018

2010 - 2012

#### **INTERESTS**

- Playing and Teaching Guitar, Teaching English, Listening to Music, Art & Technology.